[
  {
    "id": 2301,
    "question": "paciente",
    "questionDetails": "Un paciente puede estar ausente.",
    "answer": "patient",
    "answerDetails": "A patient might be missing."
  },
  {
    "id": 2302,
    "question": "gorda",
    "questionDetails": "Siempre hablaba de lo gorda que estaba.",
    "answer": "fat, fatso, plump",
    "answerDetails": "She would talk about how fat she was."
  },
  {
    "id": 2303,
    "question": "tranquilízate",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Tranquilízate ya mismo!-¡ No me voy a tranquilizar!.",
    "answer": "calm yourself",
    "answerDetails": "Calm yourself right now!-I will not calm myself!."
  },
  {
    "id": 2304,
    "question": "baje",
    "questionDetails": "¿Dónde está la biblioteca?-Baje al primer piso.",
    "answer": "go downstairs",
    "answerDetails": "Where’s the library?-Go downstairs to the first floor."
  },
  {
    "id": 2305,
    "question": "repito",
    "questionDetails": "No, repito, no cambio pañales.",
    "answer": "repeat",
    "answerDetails": "I do not, repeat, do not change diapers."
  },
  {
    "id": 2306,
    "question": "genio",
    "questionDetails": "Juanita está aprendiendo a controlar su genio.",
    "answer": "temper",
    "answerDetails": "Juanita is learning to control her temper."
  },
  {
    "id": 2307,
    "question": "desapareció",
    "answer": "he was gone"
  },
  {
    "id": 2308,
    "question": "civil",
    "questionDetails": "Es un tribunal civil.",
    "answer": "civil, marital, calendar",
    "answerDetails": "This is a civil court."
  },
  {
    "id": 2309,
    "question": "explicaciones",
    "questionDetails": "Otras tablas podrían también usar explicaciones más completas.",
    "answer": "explanations",
    "answerDetails": "Other charts could also use more comprehensible explanations."
  },
  {
    "id": 2310,
    "question": "acompañe",
    "questionDetails": "Invito a la prensa a que me acompañe.",
    "answer": "accompany, escort",
    "answerDetails": "I invite the media to accompany me."
  },
  {
    "id": 2311,
    "question": "consiguió",
    "questionDetails": "Me encanta su chaqueta. Creo que la consiguió en Europa.",
    "answer": "got it, it got",
    "answerDetails": "I love his jacket. I think he got it in Europe."
  },
  {
    "id": 2312,
    "question": "echó",
    "questionDetails": "Pero su amiga echó atrás la cabeza.",
    "answer": "threw, burst, cast",
    "answerDetails": "But her friend threw back his head."
  },
  {
    "id": 2313,
    "question": "despedida",
    "questionDetails": "Linda hizo su despedida a su familia.",
    "answer": "farewell, parting",
    "answerDetails": "Linda bid farewell to her family."
  },
  {
    "id": 2314,
    "question": "esperen",
    "questionDetails": "Denle esto personalmente, y esperen.",
    "answer": "wait, expect, await",
    "answerDetails": "Give this to him personally, then wait."
  },
  {
    "id": 2315,
    "question": "viera",
    "questionDetails": "Debí asegurarme de que no la viera.",
    "answer": "see",
    "answerDetails": "I should have made sure she didn’t see it."
  },
  {
    "id": 2316,
    "question": "preparada",
    "questionDetails": "Yo nunca esperé que vinieras preparada.",
    "answer": "prepared, ready, poised",
    "answerDetails": "I never expected that, that you’d come prepared."
  },
  {
    "id": 2317,
    "question": "difíciles",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo que hacer algunas preguntas difíciles.",
    "answer": "difficult, hard, tough",
    "answerDetails": "I must make some difficult questions."
  },
  {
    "id": 2318,
    "question": "lujo",
    "questionDetails": "Un buen baño en el jacuzzi con una barra de chocolate oscuro. ¡ Qué lujo!.",
    "answer": "luxury",
    "answerDetails": "A soak in the hot tub with a bar of dark chocolate. What luxury!."
  },
  {
    "id": 2319,
    "question": "pata",
    "questionDetails": "¿Prefieres la carne blanca o la pata?",
    "answer": "leg, paw",
    "answerDetails": "Do you prefer the white meat or the leg?"
  },
  {
    "id": 2320,
    "question": "verlos",
    "answer": "See"
  },
  {
    "id": 2321,
    "question": "remedio",
    "questionDetails": "Ya no tiene remedio.",
    "answer": "remedy, choice, cure",
    "answerDetails": "It’s past remedy."
  },
  {
    "id": 2322,
    "question": "escondido",
    "answer": "secluded"
  },
  {
    "id": 2323,
    "question": "pasara",
    "questionDetails": "Y en este enojo, no se que te pasara.",
    "answer": "happen",
    "answerDetails": "And this madness, don’t know what happen to you."
  },
  {
    "id": 2324,
    "question": "trabajas",
    "questionDetails": "¿Trabajas en el departamento de la informática?",
    "answer": "do you work",
    "answerDetails": "Do you work in IT?"
  },
  {
    "id": 2325,
    "question": "tendríamos",
    "questionDetails": "Se suponía que tendríamos una cena tranquila.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "We were supposed to have a quiet dinner."
  },
  {
    "id": 2326,
    "question": "haremos",
    "questionDetails": "Haremos un comedero de madera para los pájaros.",
    "answer": "we will make",
    "answerDetails": "We will make a bird feeder out of wood."
  },
  {
    "id": 2327,
    "question": "sentar",
    "questionDetails": "Nosotras nos vamos a sentar acá.",
    "answer": "sit, lay, sit down",
    "answerDetails": "We were going to sit there."
  },
  {
    "id": 2328,
    "question": "aplauso",
    "questionDetails": "Me encanta escuchar el aplauso del público tras la actuación.",
    "answer": "clap",
    "answerDetails": "I love to hear the clap of the audience at the end of a performance."
  },
  {
    "id": 2329,
    "question": "diré",
    "questionDetails": "Juro que diré la verdad.",
    "answer": "i will tell",
    "answerDetails": "I swear I will tell the truth."
  },
  {
    "id": 2330,
    "question": "perdida",
    "questionDetails": "Me ha devuelto mi perdida juventud.",
    "answer": "lost, loss, missing",
    "answerDetails": "She has returned to me again my lost youth."
  },
  {
    "id": 2331,
    "question": "podrás",
    "questionDetails": "Sé que podrás hacerlo.",
    "answer": "can",
    "answerDetails": "I know you can."
  },
  {
    "id": 2332,
    "question": "ritmo",
    "questionDetails": "Por favor, ve más despacio. No puedo caminar a tu mismo ritmo.",
    "answer": "pace, rhythm, beat",
    "answerDetails": "Please, slow down. I can’t walk at your same pace."
  },
  {
    "id": 2333,
    "question": "aires",
    "answer": "Aires"
  },
  {
    "id": 2334,
    "question": "viernes",
    "answer": "Friday"
  },
  {
    "id": 2335,
    "question": "miguel",
    "answer": "Miguel"
  },
  {
    "id": 2336,
    "question": "sos",
    "answer": "SOS"
  },
  {
    "id": 2337,
    "question": "jefa",
    "questionDetails": "La jefa les dijo que enviaran las mercancías.",
    "answer": "boss",
    "answerDetails": "The boss told them to deliver the goods."
  },
  {
    "id": 2338,
    "question": "ama",
    "questionDetails": "Yo la amo, y ella me ama a mí.",
    "answer": "she loves",
    "answerDetails": "I love her, and she loves me."
  },
  {
    "id": 2339,
    "question": "prima",
    "questionDetails": "Si logras tu meta de ventas durante 8 semanas consecutivas, la compañía te regala una prima de $500.",
    "answer": "bonus",
    "answerDetails": "If you hit your sales goal for 8 consecutive weeks, the company gives you a $500 bonus."
  },
  {
    "id": 2340,
    "question": "andan",
    "questionDetails": "Dicen que aquí las cosas no andan bien.",
    "answer": "are",
    "answerDetails": "They say things are no good in this house."
  },
  {
    "id": 2341,
    "question": "capital",
    "questionDetails": "Mi padre me dejó la mitad del capital.",
    "answer": "capital, equity, principal",
    "answerDetails": "My father left me half the capital."
  },
  {
    "id": 2342,
    "question": "acuérdate",
    "questionDetails": "Acuérdate de por qué lo estamos haciendo.",
    "answer": "remember",
    "answerDetails": "Remember why we´re doing this."
  },
  {
    "id": 2343,
    "question": "negar",
    "questionDetails": "Obviamente,quería negar que estaba en un casino.",
    "answer": "deny",
    "answerDetails": "Obviously he was tryingto deny it was a gambling house."
  },
  {
    "id": 2344,
    "question": "cuidando",
    "questionDetails": "Me querías en casa cuidando de los niños.",
    "answer": "taking care, caring, minding",
    "answerDetails": "You wanted me at home taking care of the kids."
  },
  {
    "id": 2345,
    "question": "enterado",
    "questionDetails": "Algunos críticos enterados la consideran la mejor novela del siglo.",
    "answer": "knowledgeable",
    "answerDetails": "Some knowledgeable critics consider it the best novel of the century."
  },
  {
    "id": 2346,
    "question": "pásame",
    "questionDetails": "Pásame el bote de las galletas.",
    "answer": "pass, Gimme",
    "answerDetails": "Pass the biscuit barrel."
  },
  {
    "id": 2347,
    "question": "patas",
    "questionDetails": "Debe tener prisa, mueve las patas rápidamente.",
    "answer": "pins",
    "answerDetails": "He must be in a hurry. His pins are moving fast."
  },
  {
    "id": 2348,
    "question": "volviste",
    "questionDetails": "Porque tú te volviste un problema.",
    "answer": "become",
    "answerDetails": "Because you become a problem."
  },
  {
    "id": 2349,
    "question": "sigamos",
    "questionDetails": "Prefiero que sigamos con el protocolo.",
    "answer": "follow",
    "answerDetails": "I prefer to follow the protocol."
  },
  {
    "id": 2350,
    "question": "pongan",
    "questionDetails": "Pongan sus cajas a un lado.",
    "answer": "put",
    "answerDetails": "Put your lockers away."
  },
  {
    "id": 2351,
    "question": "soltar",
    "questionDetails": "Activistas soltaron los chimpancés de sus jaulas.",
    "answer": "free, drop",
    "answerDetails": "Activists freed the chimps from their cages."
  },
  {
    "id": 2352,
    "question": "comunicación",
    "questionDetails": "Demoler las convenciones de su comunicación.",
    "answer": "communication",
    "answerDetails": "To undermine the conventions of its communication."
  },
  {
    "id": 2353,
    "question": "paro",
    "questionDetails": "El paro ha empujado a muchos jóvenes a marcharse del país.",
    "answer": "unemployment, stoppage, strike",
    "answerDetails": "Unemployment has driven many young people to leave the country."
  },
  {
    "id": 2354,
    "question": "invitado",
    "questionDetails": "El Dr. Gervais será un conferenciante invitado en el congreso.",
    "answer": "visiting",
    "answerDetails": "Dr. Gervais will be a visiting speaker at the conference."
  },
  {
    "id": 2355,
    "question": "bola",
    "questionDetails": "La forma en que se colocan las bolas depende del juego de billar que estés jugando.",
    "answer": "ball, fib",
    "answerDetails": "The way you rack the balls depends on which game of billiards you’re playing."
  },
  {
    "id": 2356,
    "question": "números",
    "questionDetails": "Comprobamos los números de serie y coincidieron.",
    "answer": "numbers, numerals, issues",
    "answerDetails": "We checked the serial numbers and they matched."
  },
  {
    "id": 2357,
    "question": "desaparecido",
    "questionDetails": "Militares enumerados como desaparecidos en acción.",
    "answer": "missing",
    "answerDetails": "Servicemen listed as missing in action."
  },
  {
    "id": 2358,
    "question": "pollo",
    "questionDetails": "El pollo está delicioso.",
    "answer": "chicken",
    "answerDetails": "The chicken is delicious."
  },
  {
    "id": 2359,
    "question": "ocurrir",
    "questionDetails": "No puedo creer lo que acaba de ocurrir.",
    "answer": "happen",
    "answerDetails": "I can’t believe what just happened."
  },
  {
    "id": 2360,
    "question": "estrellas",
    "questionDetails": "Algunas personas vienen aquí para ser estrellas.",
    "answer": "star",
    "answerDetails": "Some people come here to be a star."
  },
  {
    "id": 2361,
    "question": "acordar",
    "questionDetails": "Acordaron que había que limpiar el parque.",
    "answer": "agree",
    "answerDetails": "They agreed that the park needed to be cleaned up."
  },
  {
    "id": 2362,
    "question": "probable",
    "questionDetails": "Especulación sobre el efecto probable de optar por.",
    "answer": "likely",
    "answerDetails": "Speculation on the likely effect of opting out."
  },
  {
    "id": 2363,
    "question": "viniendo",
    "questionDetails": "Los buques estan viniendo por nosotros.",
    "answer": "coming, comin’",
    "answerDetails": "The boats are coming for us."
  },
  {
    "id": 2364,
    "question": "construir",
    "questionDetails": "A partir de estos datos, podemos construir modelos que pronostiquen el comportamiento de las variables.",
    "answer": "construct",
    "answerDetails": "From this data, we can construct predictive models for the variables."
  },
  {
    "id": 2365,
    "question": "comienza",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando Amos Le dice a Joan que la deja, ella comienza a llorar.",
    "answer": "she begins, he starts, it begins",
    "answerDetails": "When Amos tells Joan he’s leaving her, she begins to cry."
  },
  {
    "id": 2366,
    "question": "agente",
    "questionDetails": "Descubrieron que era Agente Secreto del FBI.",
    "answer": "agent, broker",
    "answerDetails": "He was unmasked as an undercover agent for the FBI."
  },
  {
    "id": 2367,
    "question": "boda",
    "answer": "Wedding"
  },
  {
    "id": 2368,
    "question": "ja",
    "questionDetails": "Me dijo que el auto era suyo. ¡ Ja!, sé de buena tinta que es de su hermano.",
    "answer": "ha",
    "answerDetails": "He told me the car was his. Ha! I know very well that it’s his brother’s."
  },
  {
    "id": 2369,
    "question": "oigan",
    "answer": "Hey, yo"
  },
  {
    "id": 2370,
    "question": "créeme",
    "questionDetails": "No quieres estar cerca de Charlottle cuando está enojada. Créeme.",
    "answer": "trust me",
    "answerDetails": "You don’t want to be around Charlotte when she’s angry. Trust me."
  },
  {
    "id": 2371,
    "question": "madrid",
    "answer": "Madrid"
  },
  {
    "id": 2372,
    "question": "visitar",
    "questionDetails": "Si quieren visitar el castillo, hay que reservar con antelación.",
    "answer": "go around",
    "answerDetails": "If you want to go around the castle, you have to book in advance."
  },
  {
    "id": 2373,
    "question": "acepto",
    "questionDetails": "Te acepto como eres, cariño.",
    "answer": "accept, agree",
    "answerDetails": "I accept you the way you are, darling."
  },
  {
    "id": 2374,
    "question": "matan",
    "questionDetails": "Los favores matan antes que una bala.",
    "answer": "kill",
    "answerDetails": "Favor going to kill you faster than a bullet."
  },
  {
    "id": 2375,
    "question": "investigar",
    "questionDetails": "Estudios futuros investigarán si el uso a largo plazo de los fármacos podría prevenir el cáncer.",
    "answer": "investigate",
    "answerDetails": "Future studies will investigate whether long-term use of the drugs could prevent cancer."
  },
  {
    "id": 2376,
    "question": "verá",
    "answer": "See"
  },
  {
    "id": 2377,
    "question": "protección",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando estoy en el taller, siempre utilizo guantes como protección para evitar accidentes.",
    "answer": "guard, protection",
    "answerDetails": "At the repair shop, I always wear gloves as a guard against accidents."
  },
  {
    "id": 2378,
    "question": "besos",
    "questionDetails": "Tres besos dicen que es un vínculo amoroso.",
    "answer": "kisses",
    "answerDetails": "Three kisses says it’s a romantic attachment."
  },
  {
    "id": 2379,
    "question": "respetar",
    "questionDetails": "Respetaremos sus deseos y esparciremos sus cenizas en el desierto.",
    "answer": "respect, observe",
    "answerDetails": "We will respect his wishes and will scatter his ashes in the desert."
  },
  {
    "id": 2380,
    "question": "pagando",
    "questionDetails": "Ya estoy pagando por ello.",
    "answer": "paying, payin",
    "answerDetails": "I already am paying for it."
  },
  {
    "id": 2381,
    "question": "chino",
    "questionDetails": "Estoy estudiando chino en la universidad.",
    "answer": "chinese",
    "answerDetails": "I’m studying Chinese at university."
  },
  {
    "id": 2382,
    "question": "sentimientos",
    "questionDetails": "Me heriste mucho los sentimientos.",
    "answer": "feelings",
    "answerDetails": "You really hurt my feelings."
  },
  {
    "id": 2383,
    "question": "mereces",
    "questionDetails": "Tú mereces más que eso.",
    "answer": "deserve",
    "answerDetails": "You deserve more than this."
  },
  {
    "id": 2384,
    "question": "sepan",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero que sepan lo genial que puedes ser.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "I want them to know how great you can be."
  },
  {
    "id": 2385,
    "question": "sueldo",
    "questionDetails": "Su sueldo es bastante bueno, pero gasta demasiado en su carro.",
    "answer": "salary, wage",
    "answerDetails": "She earns a fair salary, but she spends too much on her car."
  },
  {
    "id": 2386,
    "question": "ciento",
    "questionDetails": "Ciento trece kilos con cincuenta gramos.",
    "answer": "hundred",
    "answerDetails": "A hundred and thirteen kilos and fifty grams."
  },
  {
    "id": 2387,
    "question": "escuche",
    "questionDetails": "Entonces escuche la música, no la canción.",
    "answer": "listen, hear",
    "answerDetails": "Then listen to the music, not the song."
  },
  {
    "id": 2388,
    "question": "oferta",
    "questionDetails": "Han hecho una oferta de 575 millones de dólares por la empresa.",
    "answer": "bid, tender, sale",
    "answerDetails": "They’ve made a bid of 575 million dollars for the company."
  },
  {
    "id": 2389,
    "question": "verdadera",
    "questionDetails": "Y en los próximos días te probaré mi verdadera dedicación.",
    "answer": "true, real, genuine",
    "answerDetails": "And the next few days will prove my true devotion."
  },
  {
    "id": 2390,
    "question": "preguntarle",
    "questionDetails": "No quiero preguntarle. Quiero averiguar la respuesta por mí mismo.",
    "answer": "ask him",
    "answerDetails": "I don’t want to ask him. I want to figure out the answer by myself."
  },
  {
    "id": 2391,
    "question": "descansa",
    "questionDetails": "La mente humana jamás descansa.",
    "answer": "rest, relies",
    "answerDetails": "The human mind is never at rest."
  },
  {
    "id": 2392,
    "question": "encantan",
    "questionDetails": "A las cabras les encantan las tartas.",
    "answer": "love, enchant, adore",
    "answerDetails": "Goats really love pie."
  },
  {
    "id": 2393,
    "question": "esconder",
    "questionDetails": "Tampoco tenemos nada que esconder.",
    "answer": "conceal",
    "answerDetails": "Neither have we anything to conceal."
  },
  {
    "id": 2394,
    "question": "salgas",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca salgas de la ciudad.",
    "answer": "leave",
    "answerDetails": "Never leave the city."
  },
  {
    "id": 2395,
    "question": "estudios",
    "questionDetails": "Milena piensa seguir sus estudios en Europa.",
    "answer": "studies, education",
    "answerDetails": "Milena’s planning to continue her studies in Europe."
  },
  {
    "id": 2396,
    "question": "decide",
    "answer": "Decides"
  },
  {
    "id": 2397,
    "question": "escena",
    "questionDetails": "No Montes una escena delante de los niños.",
    "answer": "scene",
    "answerDetails": "Don’t make a scene in front of the children."
  },
  {
    "id": 2398,
    "question": "echo",
    "answer": "he threw"
  },
  {
    "id": 2399,
    "question": "curso",
    "questionDetails": "Mi decisión había parecido a ser el curso más sabio abierto a mí en el momento.",
    "answer": "course, progress, academic year",
    "answerDetails": "My decision had seemed to be the wisest course open to me at the time."
  },
  {
    "id": 2400,
    "question": "hacías",
    "questionDetails": "Haz lo que hacías antes.",
    "answer": "did",
    "answerDetails": "Go back to what you did before."
  }
]